<resources>
    <string name="app_name" translatable="false">Monitor</string>
    <string name="main_button_edytuj_cats_title">Cats</string>
    <string name="main_button_edytuj_logs_title">Logs</string>
    <string name="main_message_no_data_to_show">No data to show</string>

    <string name="settings_show_notification_title">Show notification</string>
    <string name="settings_dark_theme_title">Dark Theme</string>
    <string name="settings_help_title">Help</string>
    <string name="settings_warning_disabling_notification">Disabling the notification will make it impossible to start/stop activity tracking. Do you wish to disable it?</string>

    <string name="textual_data_total_time">Total time</string>
    <string name="textual_data_peak_day">Peak day</string>
    <string name="textual_data_standard_deviation">Standard deviation</string>
    <string name="textual_data_average_daily">Average daily</string>

    <string name="help_dialog_header">Help</string>

    <string name="help_topic_getting_started">Getting Started</string>
    <string name="help_topic_general">General</string>
    <string name="help_topic_cats">CATS</string>
    <string name="help_topic_logs">LOGS</string>

    <string name="dialog_button_save">save</string>
    <string name="dialog_button_cancel">cancel</string>
    <string name="dialog_button_help">help</string>

    <string name="logs_dialog_error_no_cat_selected">Select a category.</string>
    <string name="logs_dialog_error_start_time_not_before_end_time">Start time must be before end time.</string>
    <string name="logs_dialog_spinner_default_text">select a category…</string>

    <string name="editor_layout_button_clear">clear</string>
    <string name="editor_layout_button_change">change</string>
    <string name="editor_layout_button_add">add</string>
    <string name="editor_layout_button_delete">delete</string>

    <string name="cats_dialog_hint_title">title</string>
    <string name="cats_dialog_hint_initial">initial</string>

    <string name="graph_title_recent_days">in recent days</string>
    <string name="graph_title_24h_distribution">24 hours distribution</string>
    <string name="graph_title_weekly_distribution">days of week distribution</string>

    <string name="confirmation_dialog_title">Confirmation required</string>
    <string name="confirmation_dialog_negative_button">cancel</string>
    <string name="confirmation_dialog_positive_button">confirm</string>

    <string-array name="spinner_titles">
        <item>custom</item>
        <item>all time</item>
        <item>3 months</item>
        <item>30 days</item>
        <item>7 days</item>
        <item>yesterday</item>
        <item>today only</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="help_universal_getting_started">
        Welcome to Monitor![p]Monitor helps you track your activities and provides a bunch of charts and stats regarding the categories of activity you\'ve defined.[/p]

        First TODO:[p]In order to start using the app, you need to define categories of activities, eg. Studying, Training, Social media. For each of the categories, you also need to define
        a short name or emoji - such that fits well when there is little space, best an initial or a single emoji. So for example Training would get a T. The initials/emojis you define will be shown on the app\'s notification
        that\'s why it\'s best to restrict them to a single character - you may need to fit many of those. Tap CATS button in the app and an interface will pop up letting you add the categories.[/p]

        Using the app[p]Once you\'ve defined the categories and their initials, you can close the app and start using it. When you start doing one of the things you\'ve added as categories, you just tap the initial
        of that category on the app\'s notification. When you\'re done - tap it again. The app will then save a log of your activity - it\'s start time, end time and category.[/p]
    </string>
    <string name="help_universal_general">
        Pie chart[p]The grand pie chart is not just for show. You can tap any slice on it, thus selecting it. Once you do, only the data regarding that slice - the category of activity it represents,
        will be displayed on the other charts and in the stats below. When the chart shows a no-data message - it means there is no data to be shown in the selected date range.[/p]

        Date range[p]Data displayed on app\'s charts is bound by the range selected. By default the range is set to \"today only\" on the first day the app is being used, and \"3 months\" later on.
        It\'s important to realize that the range is inclusive at the start but exclusive at the end. It is because date selected means 00:00 time of day on that date. You can change the range either by using predefined
        values in the spinner under the pie chart (most of which don\'t include the current day - this is to ensure comparing apples to apples, rather than a full previous day to say 10 first hours of the current one),
        or by tapping dates below the spinner. In order to encompass the current day, set the end of the range to the beginning of the next day.[/p]

        Recent days chart[p] The second chart, under the pie, represents activity time on consecutive days within the range selected. It will, however, trim the past and start with the first day in range where there was any logged activity.
        Values are by design relative, just for visual comparison, but for convenience a scale replacement is available: tap at a given level within the graph and a horizontal line will appear along with a value in hours:minutes format
        at that level.[/p]

        Weekly distribution chart[p]Similar to the 24 hour distribution above it, the \"days of week distribution\" chart shows how days of week compare in terms of time of activity. Chart, starting with Monday,
        represents 7 days of week with relative time of activity in each of them, on average, within date range set as well as respecting selection(or lack thereof) on the pie chart.[/p]
    </string>
    <string name="help_universal_cats">
        Categories[p]CATS stands for categories. They are basically the kinds of activities to track. Playing sports, Shopping, Running, Gaming - anything that takes time and you might want to know how much of your
        time you spend on it.
        On the list in the CATS editor, they appear in the following format: initial, title, active/inactive check box[/p]

        Cats editor[p] When you press the CATS button in the app, CATS editor will open up. In the editor you can add, reorder, delete and activate/deactivate categories.[/p]

        Adding categories[p] In Cats editor, tap the round button with a plus. Type the title of the category you wish to add, then move to the next text field and add an initial - a single letter representation of the category (you can also use an emoji).
        The initial will later appear on the notification. After adding both the title and the initial, press the SAVE button. Repeat the above steps to add further categories.[/p]

        Initials[p] Initials are short names for the categories, preferably a single letter. They are displayed on the notification, where they represent the categories they were assigned to.
        When you tap the initial (on the notification), the app will take it as a signal that you\'ve started an activity in a given category. Tap it again when you stop.[/p]

        Changing an initial[p] If you wish to change an initial for an existing category, tap that category on the list in the CATS editor, change the initial in the second text input field and tap SAVE.[/p]

        Active/Inactive cats[p] You can deactivate a category by unchecking the check box next to it in the CATS editor. The inactive category will be shown on the charts but not on the notification - freeing up some space there.[/p]

        Deleting cats[p] In order to delete a category, tap it in the CATS editor\'s list and then tap DELETE.
        Deleted cats are no longer visible on the charts nor in the CATS editor. The logs of activity related to them, however,
        are not lost. Once the category is re-added, the logs will be visible on the charts again - it just has to have the exact same title.
        The app remembers titles of the deleted categories and will suggest them as you enter a new title in the CATS editor.[/p]

        Reordering cats[p] To reorder categories, press and hold a handle next to it in the list in the CATS editor and move it to it\'s new position. The new order will also appear on the notification.[/p]
    </string>
    <string name="help_universal_logs">
        Logs[p] Logs of activity are saved instances of time spent on activity of a given category. For example when you start activity in Running category, by pressing R on the notification,
        the app saves the start time. Once you tap on the R again, to finish the activity, the app reaches back to the saved start data
        and generates a log of activity which is then saved to the database. Therefore you only see logs appearing in LOGS editor after the activity is finished.
        On the list in the LOGS editor, they appear in the following format: duration, category title, start time and date.[/p]

        Logs editor[p] Tapping LOGS in the app will open up LOGS editor. This simple, yet powerful, tool allows you to change, delete and add logs of activity. Forgot to start? Left it on overnight by mistake? You can reverse any of these common
        errors.[/p]

        Adding logs[p] Open LOGS editor, tap the round plus button, select category then select start time and the end time. Press SAVE button.[/p]

        Deleting logs[p] Open LOGS editor, tap the log you wish to remove and press delete.[/p]

        Changing logs[p] Open LOGS editor, tap the log, you wish to change, on the list. Edit either category or start/end times, then tap SAVE.[/p]
    </string>

    <string name="notification_no_categories_message">tap to add categories</string>
    <string name="notification_channel_sound_title">notification controls</string>
    <string name="notification_channel_sound_description">The sole notification in this channel works as a remote and is the only mean of letting the app know when work starts/ends within a given category.</string>
    <string name="notification_channel_silent_title">silent notification controls</string>
    <string name="notification_channel_silent_description">The sole notification in this channel works as a remote and is the only mean of letting the app know when work starts/ends within a given category. This channel\'s notification should make no sound.</string>

    <string name="easy_ui_button_delete">delete</string>
    <string name="easy_ui_button_save">save</string>
    <string name="easy_ui_button_cancel">cancel</string>

    <string name="pop_up_got_it">got it</string>

    <string name="easy_ui_logs_minihelp_category">Tap on the category selection field, select category from the drop down list.</string>
    <string name="easy_ui_logs_minihelp_start_time">Select time when the activity began. Touch time, hours and minutes, to change time. Tap date if you need to change it too.</string>
    <string name="easy_ui_logs_minihelp_end_time">Select time when the activity ended. Touch time, hours and minutes, to change time. Tap date if you need to change it too.</string>
    <string name="easy_ui_logs_tv_start_time">Started at:</string>
    <string name="easy_ui_logs_tv_end_time">Ended at:</string>
    <string name="easy_ui_logs_title">Logs</string>

    <string name="easy_ui_cats_minihelp_title">Name the category of activity. For example: Running, Studying, Reading, Training.</string>
    <string name="easy_ui_cats_minihelp_initial">Assign an initial or an emote to the category. It will be displayed on the notification, where you will be tapping it to start/stop counting time spent on the category of activity - much like a stopwatch button.</string>
    <string name="easy_ui_cats_minihelp_active">If checked, the category\'s initial, as defined above, will appear on the notification as a start/stop button. You can uncheck it to temporarily hide the category from the notification.</string>
    <string name="easy_ui_cats_show_on_notification">Show on notification</string>
    <string name="easy_ui_cats_hint_initial">initial or emoji</string>
    <string name="easy_ui_cats_hint_title">Title of the category</string>

    <string name="easy_ui_cats_title">Categories</string>
    <string name="cats_dialog_error_no_title">Give the category a title.</string>
    <string name="cats_dialog_error_no_initial">Choose an initial or an emoji.</string>
    <string name="cats_dialog_error_title_is_taken">Category already exists.</string>
    <string name="cats_dialog_error_long_initial">Consider using a single letter or a single emoji.</string>


</resources>
